hello everyone we are here at SAS
inovate on tour in Mumbai where experts
and thought leaders are coming together
to explore New Frontiers on data and Ai
and I have the pleasure of Hosting none
other than Mr Gish nyak Chief technology
Health underwriting and claims at icsa
Lombard which is the largest private
non-life insurer in India welcome Gish
thanks great to have you here U now you
have a dual role you're chief of
Technology but you are also someone
who's responsible for delivering new
products and services in health
insurance as well as Wellness what are
some of those ways that analytics is
helping you do just
that great question and uh I think uh
it's it's fortunate I have both roles
and I can see how uh on every time I
look at my health portfolio I see how
technology can help me uh drive a lot
value for uh the organization on the
health front I think uh the prime mode
in which we are doing it uh is through
our I take care app and we kind of
launched this app uh around four years
back MH uh and when we launch a app I
mean when normally when someone uh
launches app you first of look at what
is the revenue what is the uh business
you can get from it but the whole
thought process behind launching that
app was was completely different there
was no Revenue Focus there was
absolutely no uh uh metric related to uh
Top Line it was completely uh designed
to be an engagement tool because uh in a
health in any kind of insurance business
you really are not in touch with the
customer okay so customer buys a policy
and uh if there's no claim and in health
the claims claim uh incidents will be
about 8 to 9% so more than 90% of
customers don't even touch B with you
for the entire till the renewal is due
right so there is really uh no ability
to experience engage with uh uh the
insurer and
uh the thought process behind launching
the app was how do you do that so uh we
started putting on lot of services and
uh engagement tools on how the customer
can look after his or her uh Fitness
well-being uh health
and just coincidential at the time we
had launched it we just about few months
from the launch that uh Co happened and
at that point in time it became really
beneficial to have the app on and uh a
lot of services Like Home Care uh telec
consult all this your complete health
risk assessment which you could do on
the app all this we could then build out
on the app and deliver it to our
customers and help them kind of uh
benefit from that uh those services in
fact we also had a face scan uh feature
where you just look at the app for a
couple of minutes with the camera and
then it can give you your blood pressure
heart rate spo2 levels and you know in
Co people were measuring their spo2
levels so that's the background now why
talking about all this but because this
is what we are giving our customers and
customers are engaging with us on the
app but at a lot of at the same time
it's giving us a lot of data about the
customers right right uh when you do a
face scan I am uh having access to how
you are uh what are your health
parameters on a regular basis if you do
you if you check your face scan say once
a month or once in two months I keep
having your uh health
so to say at if you do a health risk
assessment I do get more metrics on yes
if you are measuring your steps
I understand how fit your or level of
Fitness that you're kind of so all this
data is extremely valuable when it comes
to underwriting right so uh the whole uh
idea is we are are we able to then use
this data to help uh design better
products for the customer and offer
better pricing to the customer customer
right so that's one the other is of of
course on uh in the same uh manner uh we
write a lot of group health business
right and there a lot of customers we
have in the group health business who
are also part of the platform uh now can
we sell something to them which is or
because typically a corporate policy
covers say uh 4 lakhs 5
lakhs better corporates cover 10 lakhs
of not enough insurance cover right sure
but then you have all the data related
to uh that corporate policy uh with you
right can you then based on the data
offer a better uh product to these
customers which covers the additional uh
uh requirements so for example a topup
which is priced substantially cheaper
than what uh a normal topup would cost
because I already have the base data on
the customer and the burning layer is
taken care of right so a lot of
datadriven
uh uh uh tools which help you to design
better products and uh maintain price
competitiveness in terms of the products
you offer to customers uh definitely uh
are being uh used through this whole uh
platform yeah I think certainly a lot of
possibilities there considering you know
the sort of data that can you enable uh
you to kind of bring out some of those
products U thank you for that Insight U
fish um now from a large language model
standpoint from an AI standpoint there's
been a lot of talk about Enterprise
adoption and scaling it but a lot of
that tends to be focused on the realm of
customer service um are there any use
cases or ideas that you are exploring in
terms of um bringing that outside the
realm of customer
service for sure um I think uh one clear
uh place where we are uh using this uh
uh co-pilots and this very uh nicely is
in our with our development team right
and it does cut down the time for
development at least by 25 30% uh in
lots of cases MH uh and that's that's a
great help right it gets you uh up to
speed faster and then uh you it takes
away a large amount of the mundan
develop tasks out of the uh picture so
that's one place definitely that we are
seeing uh benefits of using uh these
models uh the other place where we have
used it I mean not that we will try and
use it we have used it and we have done
something uh we launched
uh and this is some six months back we
launched our first uh marketing campaign
was completely built using AI okay so
that was it was only on digital media
but uh I think we were one of the first
companies I or could be the first
company to do completely uh AI generated
uh marketing campaign wonder the whole
video all the three four different
videos that were there for the campaign
were generated by AI so we have uh and
in marketing we use AI quite effectively
in terms of personalizing uh videos for
customers right um again the AI uh tools
help uh is basically with Gen coming in
all these tools are available to you to
use
uh uh in this fashion u in business
uh summarization is a big uh use case
for uh large language models U one thing
where we we are experimenting with it is
in terms of our uh medical claims
processing so once uh you have the
entire discharge summary and the whole
uh bills and everything that come to you
as a entire set of documents
you look through documents doctor reads
through them it treats or discharge
summary tries to figure out okay if uh
the patient was hospitalized for Deni so
hospitalization should have been for 4
days this should have been the medicine
prescribed blah blah blah and then sees
whether the uh treatment has been as per
the uh protocol now uh with Gen you can
just feed all that to the model and the
model come up with what is the standard
treatment protocol what is the
treatment given what is the difference
and highlighting whether something more
or something less has been done right so
it saves a great deal of time for the
Doctor Who's adjudicating the claim in
terms of pre-processing it and the
doctor just looks at it and says okay
this seems to be in line let's go so
those are some of the areas where
besides chat Boards of course chat
boards you do the regular stuff but uh
these are some of the use cases we
seeing jni uh tools being used uh apart
from chatbots very interesting indeed
and um thanks again for your valuable
perspectives I personally learned a lot
so thank you for having this
conversation with us today Gish thanks
be my pleasure